i'm originally from the state of florida
but you already knew that because you
can hear the white trash in my voice
[Laughter]
[Music]
i mean i spent 29 years in florida
before i moved to l.a i was
it was the summers that's what killed me
every year if you've never been to
florida in the summer it's like spending
three months inside someone's mouth
just hot and sticky
and draw oh my oh my goodness driving
i drove from east to west i drove from
florida to california club have you ever
done that
you hear all the sad that clatter sounds
because it's the worst drive ever you
know why because texas exists
that state is a thousand miles of suck
it's terrible
[Laughter]
and i'd like to remind you about how far
you are from nothing
i left houston the next sign i saw was
el paso 5
46.
are you
kidding
me why even put that
just put what you honestly mean el paso
tomorrow
[Laughter]
[Music]
new mexico maybe
if you take texas off the map it is 45
minutes from florida to california
flat
and then i moved to la and people were
passive aggressively rude to me when
they found out iris from florida they
would form it in the pros of a question
to kind of get underneath my skin like
oh you're from florida
what's that like
it's a peninsula
you want some i didn't grow up in a
trash fire i grew up in the
sunshine but i have like 10 people asked
that same question i had to do some
self-state reflection
and then i realized something about
florida florida is the dive bar of the
united states
it's that bar when you ride by you
leaning your butt and go that's where i
get all my drugs
the exact moment you say that a dude
stumbles out of that bar with a gunshot
wound an alligator grabs him drags him
to a walmart where judo bath sauce kills
the alligator
that's where i'm from
i want to answer your next question yes
i have a gun but it's on my ankle so
we're all safe
[Laughter]
because you got to make me really mad to
want to start leaning towards that thing
just
[Music]
no i'm actually from florida now i'm a
florida boy i was born in michigan but i
i live in florida now and so it's a far
ride thank you another one excellent
scattered about it's a far ride from
florida i ubered here to get here to
utah so
1700 ubers so that was
a wonderful thing florida what we have
in florida we have the hurricanes in
florida you guys don't have to deal with
that i moved down to florida and it was
like four or five hurricanes hit us in a
row i didn't know what to do so everyone
gives you advice in florida they say get
to home depot go to home depot casey go
to home depot
get your supplies so i ran to home depot
i didn't know what to do after that
so i'm like i'm just gonna follow this
old guy around i'm gonna get whatever he
gets so i got what he got i got wood i
got nails i got water and a six foot
pink flamingo
i don't know how they do it down here
and the weathermen love hurricanes they
love it because they're the stars now
everyone's watching the weather channel
and they ruin it for us because these
weathermen don't really know anything
anyways they're like we got the doppler
13 1400 000 we know exactly where this
hurricane's going
so if you're in the west palm beach area
get ready in our cone but also get ready
provo utah area somewhere in this cone
we know nothing we know nothing at all
we're guessing thank you thank you
[Applause]
i don't like any hurricanes at all i
don't even like the miami hurricanes the
college
no well i went to florida state
university and i'm a seminal and if you
go to florida the college scene is a big
rivalry and the hurricanes are the worst
because they talk trash 24 7. even the
offseason they're talking trash i'm
wearing my fsu shirt the other day a guy
comes up to me he's like your seminals
it's all about the you baby we're going
to kick your butt and we're going to do
it again and again and again
[Applause]
i go hey that's great i went to school
for an education not football
and can you finish pumping my gas i got
to get out of here
i got a sweet 50 gig at the comedy
corner in fort pierce
so provo by way of florida i was just in
florida i was in saint augustine florida
which by the way i don't know if you
know this or not saint augustine florida
is the oldest city
in the united states you can go there
and see all the buildings that they
built way back in the 1500s and then you
can go to tampa and you can actually
meet the people that built them
then you can drive down to naples and
meet their parents
there's a lot of old people in florida
i was at a walmart the greeter said can
i get you a basket
[Laughter]
i don't know can you
clear
can i get you a casket
no it's a super center you know they
sell them
and listen i'm not talking old like 80
or 90. my mother and father are that age
i'm talking people in their late 100s
early 200s
i mean they would come to my shows like
this and stare at me like the amish at
best buy
i've never actually seen dead people sit
up
the very first time i was ever down in
florida i was in miami beautiful city by
the way miami florida and i'm playing
golf with a friend of mine who grew up
in the state of florida on the golf
course with us and apparently this is
very popular is an alligator and i'm
freaking out and my friend he doesn't
even flinch he just looks at me he goes
you know russ hey buddy hey bro hey man
now those alligators they can run 35
miles an hour
not if he's chasing me he'll be slipping
in some poop
i'll see you at the windmill
i'm gonna tell you guys a story about my
grandma uh this is very true i went back
home and i visited my grandma my
grandmother helped raise me she's my
favorite people in the world i went back
home i guess in the two years since i
had gone back home
she had come down with a pretty bad case
of dementia and when i mentioned it to
my dad who had been dealing with for two
years he's like yeah
i don't know what happened it's like we
took her to florida and she came back
with alzheimer's
well okay well i don't think that's how
it works
um
but here's my point uh if you have a
grandma
maybe keep her out of florida for a few
years
just to be on the safe side right who's
to say
so we all followed the election and it
comes down to the swing states they make
it too complicated basically if you win
ohio and florida you will be the
president right so i'm telling you right
now a future president is lebron james
everybody that guy's gonna be friends
[Applause]
he's got ohio wrapped up right and he
won two titles in florida but maybe if
he needs help with the older voters his
running mate jimmy buffett done deal
right there fun deal
a bumper sticker the king james buffet
right there
okay my wife gave me very good advice to
keep friends she said if a friend tells
you bad news in their life you just say
i'm sorry to hear that
and nothing else
[Music]
she also said buy them a card or a gift
because actions speak louder than words
and that is very good advice a week
later my friend told me that he had been
diagnosed with lyme disease so i said
i'm sorry to hear that
nothing else
got him to get well card too and i put a
coupon in for limeade
because
you know why you know why i did that
my other friend
he went to florida and got his hand bit
off by an alligator because they jump
out of trees now and
it's real google it bedroom and uh
it jumped out of a tree and it bit his
hand off and he hated the gatorade
so
so i have to tell you this i uh
i decided to kind of get honest with the
my uh audience and just kind of open up
to them and tell them all about me even
though i wear this cowboy hat i was born
in florida i know you're thinking wow
sure a lot of cowboys come from florida
right
no
especially from south florida that's
where i was born
and uh
i tell you i hate it down there
math in south florida was different than
math anywhere else in the whole united
states our questions in elementary
school were like um
jose has a speedboat going 74 miles an
hour
carrying 14 kilos of illicit substance
the coast guard has an airplane going
183 miles an hour
how long do the kilos sink to the bottom
of the ocean
they made us take spanish in first grade
first grade first day of school they
give you this big workbook you learn
stuff like como estas how are you
one my name is john then you go to some
of the places where people only speak
spanish
like cozumel or honduras or california
and you um
[Laughter]
i thought that's how you're going to
react to that
you go como estas me i'm juan that guy
goes
you guys look great i just want to tell
you i can see you this is kind of a rare
treat a lot of times it's just a sea of
blackness out there we can't see faces
but the way you're lit i like seeing
your faces you all look very young and
healthy
of course last week i was in florida so
i thought that was a myth
i thought that was a gross over
generalization the old people going to
florida i'm not kidding you i got on the
plane in denver to fly to miami and i
realized
i'm the only one who did not pre-board
anyone needs the extra time getting to
their seat they come to our gate now
and the walkers were sparking
there was a locker fight at one point i
don't know if you've seen that get back
if you see a walker fight those little
tennis balls on the end go flying
scary
i got on the plane it was beautiful it
was like a sea of cotton balls ahead of
me
caps
i thought the whole plane was going to
go towards the light
next stop heaven
so now i live in florida um i took my
kids to the beach on saturday
yeah that's awesome
you gotta be careful like i took the
beach it was a beach clothing was
optional i was like oh we're out of here
and we left right away but i noticed the
one good thing about a beach like that
is on that kind of beach i'm a good
looking man
there's a lot of ugly people dude
put your shirt on buddy
the horses are trying to eat
it's got to stay healthy right that's it
you got to travel right i'm saying
that's healthy right traveling
i've been traveling a lot started doing
cruises
because that's where my career is headed
i like it though man i like it getting
me out of those cold new jersey winners
that's important right
like they always send me down to uh
florida plantation fort have i ever
heard of plantation florida
yeah
i hadn't
and let me tell you something i was
nervous
the whole time
i was in plantation florida
i was like y'all gonna let me leave here
i don't want no problems with my
departure
it felt weird getting the cab somehow
take me to plantation
hurry up i'm late
i went from plantation to the boat
talk about how things have changed
[Music]
what obama was talking about
i don't know man facebook it's gotten
it's gotten weird like
really weird
in the last 10 years it's gotten like
i don't know it's gotten me thinking
like
here's what i think about i think it's
turned into florida
i think facebook is a lot like florida
because it started out as a place for
college kids to go and have fun
and then the old people came in and took
over
i didn't even know you could misspell
lol until they got on there like
i embrace cultural diversity one of my
favorite cities on the planet is miami
florida and i was heartbroken when i
recommended miami to a manly man friend
of mine back in ohio and he said i hated
miami dude nobody spoke english to me
down there if all those cupids and
puerto ricans don't want to learn
english they should just go back to
mexico where they came from
i said you should go back to school or
you dropped out of
folks i've been playing and enjoying
miami for over two decades now and i
found a way to get latino miamians to
speak to me
in rapid fire perfectly accented english
and that's by speaking to them
in horribly accented painfully slow
spanish
excuse me sir could you please tell me
where i find the nearest cvs drugstore
around here oh lo siento si no no hablo
ingles no
two stop lights you take a left at the
post office
[Music]
so i do i love being a desk my favorite
job
that's the question i get is your kids
funny and all all my kids are funny but
xander
my middle one is the funniest kid uh
uh i was actually backstage trying to
think of some examples oh um this summer
he uh i took him to uh i should have
planned this out uh not
philadelphia the other one
uh florida um
i knew it was a state that started with
an f
[Music]
don't laugh at me i am not good at
geometry um
now it was florida i was doing a
pastor's conference it was like 300
pastors and xander was backstage and he
was looking out and he's like is that a
room full of pastors and i was like yeah
and he goes how long's your show and i
go i'm doing an hour and he goes good
go twice as long so they'll see how it
feels
and you got to watch what you say too as
you get older you lose your filter i was
doing a show in florida and the
audiences they're a little bit older
they don't use uber they call an
ambulance just in case
[Music]
after the show this woman comes up to me
she goes out was so funny i couldn't
believe it when you said you were 65 i
said to my friend he doesn't look 65 but
now that i see you up close you kind of
do
but it's not just my group the baby
boomers who are getting up there
generation x is 52 years old now ladies
and gentlemen remember them the punk
rockers they're getting up there just
the other day i saw it a guy wearing a
mohawk toupee i couldn't believe it
tight black jeans size 46 waistline
combat boots with velcro straps
my dad he's doing crazy things i'm even
more concerned about my mom and i warned
you about her
since my mom has retired
my mom has now
joined a gang
no my mom's joined a gang she now has a
silk jacket it's got letters on the prop
all across the back of it she's got a
great big gold and silver emblem on the
back of her car that says something like
aarp yo
yeah and i don't know what the motto of
the aarp is but i'm sure it's something
like we're old we're bold we will not
stand our coffee cold
yeah we're rich
and now we go to florida during the
winter to spend our kids inheritance
yeah
that's a lot more funny to those people
right now than it really is to me
but my parents in the last couple years
they kind of became full-time snowbirds
you guys know what the definition of a
snowbird is don't you it's someone that
moves from a
cold climate to a warm climate doing the
excuse me during the winter time only to
call back up here everyday and ask me
what the weather's like
[Music]
is it true sir
i get that call it's about 6 40 every
morning it's always ring ring ring ring
and it says sarasota florida and i got
to pick the phone up because this might
be the day i get to cash that
inheritance in
[Laughter]
[Music]
yeah and i always say something stupid i
say cash call from florida
and it's always my mom no no no idiot
still not funny
don't quit your day job go to work
it's just your mom i'm calling to see
what the weather's like in michigan
today
i said what's the weather like in
michigan mom you guys still have that
big screen tv down there in your condo
yeah and you still watch the weather
channel from like four in the morning
till midnight every night
yes so about every 15 minutes you're
gonna get to know what the weather's
like here in michigan
you see that big swath of pink and white
and blue covering the whole mitten state
that should just say crap
yeah that's what the weather's gonna be
like for the next three or four months
that is why you laughed
but i'm stupid i always say this i say
you don't want to know the answer chris
you don't want to know the answer but
i'm just being nice and i say so what's
the weather like in florida and she goes
oh oh it got cold down here last night
it got down into the 40s your dad turned
the heat on i wore my long night gown
and i wore socks to bed
yeah i said
thank you mom for telling me where your
long night gown to bed because that time
you or your short night down to
breakfast
i still need therapy for that
cool you don't have to applaud for that
someone's got to do some ironing that's
all i got to say
[Music]
oh man this is awesome it's fun so if
you're going to be weird you got to step
it up also how dare austin and portland
keep it weird when how dare they act
like they're weird when they know
florida exists
yeah and it's just out there doing what
florida does
last time i was in florida this is real
by the way this is google information
after the show i'm in florida i'm
walking past a newspaper stand i look
into the stand the headline on the
newspaper reads local man robs wendy's
with alligator
what did you just say to me
i read it i still said that out loud it
was incredible
oh and also yeah that's all you want to
say you don't want to add any more to
that like i don't know maybe tell us if
the alligator was an accomplice or a
weapon how about that
for real
did this guy rob a wendy's with an
alligator or did this guy rob a wendy's
with an alligator
there's a huge difference
like did he start did you start a gang
with an alligator throw a bandanna on it
he's like we're the alligator boys now
let's get to a wendy's and make this
official
no
so
this is how i bought the paper and i
read the article and this is real he
used the alligator as a weapon okay
and when i read that i was like did he
at least hold it like a gun
right
he didn't
he threw it
through a drive-through window
yep
didn't see that one coming did
ya
you know who else did it the lady
the drive-thru
so many things have to happen before you
can even throw an alligator
have to
find it in the wild
also by the way how horrible is florida
that there is just alligators available
to you
what was even his qualifying material
was he looking for a specific type or
just the first one he saw he was like
this is the one and he took it that was
it
so this is real
this
happened
in florida a place connected to the
united states
where we are all living currently
a grown man with a driver's license
found an alligator that day he didn't
even build a relationship with it
takes his new alligator and he seat belt
it into the back seat of his car
i assume
i just have no idea how else you keep it
from getting into the front seat and
biting you right
i don't
no you guys know anything about
alligators but they kind of just do
whatever they want
[Music]
so he seatbelts this dinosaur into the
back seat
and he gets into the front seat and he's
like ah
i gotta make some money today
there's a wheel
oh i could get a job and he goes no no
time
spent most my day on that alligator
thing
projects
i could rob someone
he goes i can rob a place
those places have more money than
someone's
rob a bank and he goes no no they'll be
expecting that
he's thinking about it and then he saw
he comes to the conclusion wendy's
they have money and chili that's the
place
so he drives his new alligator to
wendy's okay
pulls up to the drive-through and the
lady at the drive-thru is like hello how
can i help you today and he goes give me
all the money and she just goes looks
right at him and goes uh no
you didn't even come inside
you failed at this robbery
and the dude is so mad he goes give me
the money in the register or i'll kill
you
and she's from florida so she's not
afraid of death or whatever
she looks down at him she's like no if
you had a gun you would have shown it to
me already i call your bluff gotta hear
crazy guy go go go
he's
seething matt at this point furious and
he's like you know what i don't have a
gun but hold on
and then he palmed an alligator
through the drive-through window
yup
he skipped so many steps in that robbery
if he had a list of things
he was supposed to do
he would have thrown the alligator
looked down and just been like oh
no
i was supposed to threaten her with the
alligator first
by the way can you imagine being her
telling this guy off and he's like you
know what i don't have a gun and you're
like wow nailed it really doing it today
and then he leads back and starts
unbuckling the world's ugliest toddler
hey someone come and see this is wild
then you look back and an alligator is
flying
imagine being the car behind him
just
sitting there with your girlfriend
like what takes so long to make burgers
here
she's on her phone you're like do you
even care you look back from her and
then an alligator soars
from window to window
honey get off your phone they're
throwing alligators and new wendy's
this guy is crazy
she's on her phone like that doesn't
make sense they don't even serve
alligators here
what why am i with you
[Laughter]
[Music]
so
this dude is sitting there
awkwardly with no more alligators left
to play in the robbery
probably thinking to himself oh you
think if i ask for my alligator back
such a bad idea to throw it he didn't
even put a fanny pack on it like
maybe get some money while you're in
there i don't know
so
he drives off
yeah and he gets arrested immediately
he didn't even wear a mask
yeah he was like i'm in florida people
throw alligators i'll probably get lost
in the shuffle
uh no he didn't
they remembered him they arrested him
pretty hard afterwards
the end of the article is true it goes
no one was injured the alligator was
safely released back into the wild at
the very end of the article it read no
drug involvement suspected
oh yeah florida
that was your sober plan
what does the non-sober plan look like
do you ride a horse and the alligator
throws you
what happens